Guide to the Harold E. Klein papers, 1980-1993.
Klein, Harold E. papers
- AKA Proposals, 1987 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  A Suggested Proposal for Humanitarian Aid
  AKA Plans for Aid Distribution
  Annual Report of the Director of Human Rights
- Burmmy AI Report, Cransten Letter, 1998 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Letters from Harold Klein to Tony and Hugh
- Miscellany, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Letters from people (e.g. United States Senate) to people (e.g. Prime Minister in Thailand)
  News about “The World Doesn’t Appear to Notice Burma’s Abuses” by Denis D. Gray
- Ba Thin, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Statement of New Mya Thaung
  Statement of Escaped Porter…
- Miscellany, 1987 - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Letters to and from Maureen Aung-Thwin
  World News about “Burma Hints at End to Regime of Isolation”
  Burma Newsletter Vol. I, No.1 1987
  Foreign Affairs, Burmese Days by Maurean Aung-Thwin, 1989
- Eric Battersby, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Message from Eric Battersby
- Baron/Canning and Company. INC., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  A Program for the Government of Kawthoolet
- Miscellany, 1988 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Burma: The Coalition’s Perspective 1992
  Senator Chris Schacht’s Burma Report 1990 - 1992
  Media Release
  News Release “Will the 27 May Election in Burma be Free and Fair?” by Senator Robert Hill Shador Minister for Foreign Affairs to the Committee for Democracy in Burma 1990
  News Release of Minister for Foreign Affairs and Trade 1989 - 1990
  Letters from people in Australia to people
  Burma: The Struggle for Democracy by Gary Woodard
  A Report Prepared by Robert Mister in 1991
- Karen Refugee Testimonies, 1986 - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  Some Testimonies of Burmese Atrocities and Violations of Human Rights
  Testimony by Former Government Soldiers
  Notes referring to the Maldon Institute Analysis on Burma 1988
  Reports from Tribal Refugee Welfare in S.E. Asia
- Miscellany, 1987 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  Annual Report by the Director of Human Rights
  New Intelligence Information from Karenni
  Top Secret Nin Yan Naing Offence – Defense Strategy
  Situation Report Presented to the Foreign Affaire Committee of the House of Commons by the Anti-Slavery Society 1987
  Report and Update on Conditions in Kachinland
  The Karenni Papers Presented by Karenni Provisional Government
  Karenni Provisional Government by Ministry of Foreign Affairs in 1992
  The Question on Karenni Sovereignty and Independence by Ministry of Foreign Affairs
  Copy Forwarded to H.E. the Governor for Information
  Statements by Karenni Refugees by Manerplaw
- Papers in International Studies, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  Southeast Asian References in the British Parliamentary Papers 1801 – 1972/73: An Index
- The Karen of Burma, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  “A” Drive Diskette
  The Karen of Burma – Their Search for Freedom and Justice by Harold E. Klein
- Miscellany, 1992 - 1995 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  The Order Issued by the Highest Honour Awarded Budhist Monks’ Purification Committee Chwired by U Nu. The Unstitution of the Budhist Clergy, Kaba-Aye, Rangoon
  Force 272 Report Transmitted by Telephone 1993
  Letter from Presbytery of Riverside to people
- Burma Debate, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  Burma Debate Vol. V, No. 4 1998
- News Reports, 1986 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  News from Asia Watch 1990 - 1991
  Human Rights in Burma for Immediate Release 1990
  Annual Report of an Asia Watch Report 1986
  Asiaweek 1991
- Asia Society, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  Pamphlet of the Asia Society
- Consortium, 1990 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  Reports on Activities from 1990 -1991
- Cultural Survival, 1987 - 1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  Cultural Survival Quarterly Vol.13 No.4 1989
  New Titles and complete catalog, Cultural Survival 1987-1988
- Reports / proposals, 1987 - 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Political Report by Aung Ye Myint
  Letter from the Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma to Harold Klein
  Twelve-point Proposal toward National Reconciliation in Commemoration of the 40th Anniversary of the Panglong Conference 1987
  To the Officers and Men of the Armed Forced of Burma in Commemoration of the 42nd Anniversary of Burma Resist Ance Day 1987
  National Democratic Front 1987
  President’s Report of Foundation for Democracy in Burma 1987
  Letters from Foundation for Democracy in Burma
  One step further: the special report of the Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma 1988
  Letters form the New Republic Party of Burma 1988
- Reports, 1989 – 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  C.R.D.B. Vol. 1. No.1-No.2 1989
  C.R.D.B. Vol. III. No 2 1990
  Statement Supporting the Burmese Student Movement for Democracy 1989
- Reports, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  News letter of Burma Association INC. 1990
  Issue Brief: Burma 1990
- Reports, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Monthly News from the Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma 1991
- Reports, 1991 - 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Media Release of Democracy in Burma 1991
  The Committee for Restoration of Democracy in Burma A.B. Aungkhin Chairman-West U.S.A.
  News & View from CRDB. 1993
  Tri-Annual Report No.1 of Southeast Asian Information Network 1993
  Report on the situation of human rights in Myanmar, prepared by Mr. Yozo Yokota, Economic and Social Council of the United Nations 1992
- Reports, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Statement on SLORC’s convening of the National Convention 1993
  Statement by the National Democratic Front on the Current Situation in Burma
  Rehmonnya Bulletin Vol. 2. No. 1-2. 1992
  Letters from National Democratic Front (Burma) to Harold Klein
  Answers to Questionnaire on Mon Freedom Movement by New Mon State Party
  Mon Young Monks Magazine Vol. 1 No.1 1992
  Top Secret Min Yan Naing Operation and Defense Plan
  Manerplaw Agreement: Agreement to Establish a Federal Union of Burma
- Enterprise for Education, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Activity Report
  Open Letter to the Prime Minister of Japan on Japanese/Burmese Relations 1990
  Concepts for Use in a Panel Presentation on Burma Problems by Dr. Marta and Others of the Panel
  News Release of International Human Rights Law Group 1990
  Memorandum 1990
  Paper Presented at Burma Seminar 1990
- Correspondence, 1986 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Letters from Karen Theological Education to Harold Klein
- Miscellany, 1993 - 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Maps – Burma – USAF
  Papers – Why Kaw Moo Ra the last stronghold of KNU fell? Because of Toxic gas and Siege Mortars
  End of Year Report on Burma/Burmese Border
  International Campaign for Buddhist Monks in Burma 1993
- Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Field Report No. 1. of Karen Youth Organization 1993
  An Independent Report by the Karen Human Rights Group 1994
  Local/Regional News 1994
  News 1994
  Asia Watch Burma Report 1994 from Human Rights Watch World Report
- Misc. Papers and Reports, 1990 - 1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  E-mails
  Monthly Report of Karen Refugee Committee 1997-1998
  Burma Destruction of the Forests by the All Burma Students’ Democratic Front
  Burma Alert Vol. 8, No. 7-9 1997
  Amnesty International 1997
  Letters from ABSDF (All Burma Students’ Democratic Front) to people
  Policy Statement of the All Burma Students’ Democratic Front on Political Strategy
- Misc. Papers, 1982-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Paper about Links Between Military and Economic Assistance
  Paper about the Perversion of Foreign Aid by Nick Eberstadt 1985
  Comprehensive Analysis of Foreign Assistance 1982
  Political Terrorism: A research guide to concepts, theories, data bases
  Washington Quarterly Vol. 6, No. 1 1983
  A proposal for Constructive Involvement 1992
- Correspondence, 1989 - 1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Letters from Amoco Corporation and Coca Cola to Harold Klein
  News about Pipeline: Charges Lead to Unocal Vote
- Miscellany, 1990 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  LA times
  Letter from people (e.g. Congress of the United States) to Harold Klein
  International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights
  Assessing the Burma Situation by Harold E. Klein 1992
  Paper about “The Election in Myanmar is Not Yet Over” by Steven M. Schneebaum 1990
- Misc. Statements and Letters, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Statement by Naw Htoo Paw, Issued at Manerplaw, Kaw Thoo Lei, 1992
- Miscellany, 1998 - 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Saw Bo Mya. 2002. Memoirs on My True Past Experiences that I Wish to Disclose
  A Report from Karen National League to the International Community 1998
  The photographs from Luthaw and Mu Traw Districts
- Plight of Minority People Report, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Burma Plight of Minority People. Report by Jubilee Campaign. 1993
- Edge of Burma Article, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Karens: The Edge of Burma by Thomas Mackin 1985
- Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Letter from Saw Htoo to people in Christ
- Hand-written Notes, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Klein’s hand written documents
- Refugees, 1985 - 1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  U.S. Committee For Refugees Publications
  Roger P. Winter. 1986. The Karen of Burma: Thailand’s Other Refugees. Issue Brief of United States Committee for Refugees
  Letters from United State Committee for Refugees to Harold Klein
  World Refugee Survey 1985 in Review
- National Democratic Front, 1988 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Letters from National Democratic Front to Harold Klein
  Statement by the National Democratic Front on the Current Situation in Burma 1988
  Guidelines for a Democratic Federation for Burma
- Miscellany, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Sketch Map of Karenni
  Graphs about food supply
  Letters from people (e.g. Patrick San Hoo, Lawrence Po, Robert Htwe, and Pla Reh) to Harold Klein
- Publication, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  Rose Alatorra. 1992. Improvements to the Educational, Agricultural, and Health Systems for the Karen Rural Development Christian Center in Amoh, Burma. San Diego State University
- Karenni Legal Issues, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  Karenni legal issues 1992 from Karen Parker and Christopher Cline to Mr. Abel Tweed, Foreign Minister Karenni Provisional Government
- The Dossier of Karenni, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  The Dossier of Karenni Presented by The Government of Karenni 1992
- Lloyd Jones, 1991 - 1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  Letters to and from Lloyd Jones
  Letters from people (e.g. Canadian Baptist Refugee Services) to Harold Klein
  At War in the Fields of the Lord by Lloyd Jones 1992
- Correspondence and Reports, 1991- 1993 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  Letters from Jubilee Campaign to Harold Klein
  Letters from Harold Klein to Jubilee Campaign
  Reports from Jubilee Campaign
  Briefing Report on Burma and the Persecution of Ethnic Karen. Published by the Jubilee Campaign 1990
  The Burma Focus Vol. 2, No. 9 1992
- Human Rights Caucus, 1985 - 1988 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  News collections
  Report of the Committee on Foreign Relations United States Senate 1985
  Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 1986 by the Department of State. 100th Congress 1st Session
  Country Reports on Human Rights Practices for 1987 by the Department of State. 100th Congress 2d Session
- IMF, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  Letters from International Monetary Fund to Harold Klein
- International Human Rights Law Group Report, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  International Human Rights Law Group. Report on the Myanmar Election 1990